creativeskillset.org 2019-04-18

# Privacy policy - ScreenSkills

We, ScreenSkills, (we/us/our), or any successor in title are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.  

This Privacy Policy (the Policy) (together with our Cookie Policy and Terms and Conditions and any other documents referred to in these documents) explains how we use any personal information about you (you/your) that we collect when you use the ScreenSkills website (www.screenskills.com) or any successor in title and any of our other online products, sub-sites and all other websites owned, operated and controlled by us (collectively, the ScreenSkills website). Please read these documents carefully. Defined words used in the Terms and Conditions shall have the same meaning when used in this Policy. References to a ‘parent’ include a legal guardian.

By using the ScreenSkills website (and in particular by submitting your personal information to us via the ScreenSkills website or, if you are a parent, by consenting for your child to do the same), you give your consent to the collection, storage and use of your or, as applicable, your child’s personal information, as described in this Policy. If you are a parent allowing your child to use the ScreenSkills website, references in this Policy to ‘your personal information’ shall be to your child’s personal information.

## Data protection compliance

The ScreenSkills website is controlled by us from our offices in the United Kingdom (UK).  Personal information collected via the ScreenSkills website is processed in compliance with the General Data Protection Guidelines of May 2018 (GDPR) and any other subsequent Data Protection Legislation UK (Act). For the purpose of the GDPR, we are registered as a Data Controller (our registration number is Z8941934) and our Data Protection Officers are:

Anna Kim, HR and Office Manager, available at [anna.kim@screenskills.com](mailto:anna.kim@screenskills.com)  
Clive Goss, Finance and Operations Director, available at [clive.goss@screenskills.com](mailto:clive.goss@screenskills.com)  
Our Data Protection Officers' general email is: [data.protection@screenskills.com](mailto:data.protection@creativeskillset.org)

If you choose to visit the ScreenSkills website from outside the UK, you do so at your own risk, with the understanding that personal information collected from the ScreenSkills website may be collected, stored and used in a country whose privacy laws may be different and less protective than those of your home country.

If you are under the age of 18, please get permission from your parent before you provide personal information through the ScreenSkills website.

## Our legal basis for processing your information

The use of your information for the purposes set out above is lawful because one or more of the following applies:

  * Where you have provided information to us for the purposes of requesting information or requesting that we carry out a service for you, we will proceed on the basis that you have given consent to us using the information for that purpose, based on the way that you provided the information to us. You may withdraw consent at any time by emailing us at [data.protection@screenskills.com](mailto:data.protection@creativeskillset.org). This will not affect the lawfulness of processing of your information prior to your withdrawal of consent being received and actioned.
  * Where you have created a profile on one of our web products, where we would collect/record your consent for provision of your account and relevant service.
  * It is necessary for us to hold and use your information so that we can carry out our obligations under a contract entered into with you or to take steps you ask us to prior to entering into a contract.
  * Where necessary to comply with our legal obligations.
  * Where the purpose of our processing is the provision of information or services to you, we may also rely on the fact that it is necessary for your legitimate interests that we provide the information or service requested, and given that you have made the request, would presume that there is no prejudice to you in our fulfilling your request.
  * Where necessary, the provision of information to a third party to enable them to fulfil part of a contract or request for assistance such as third party training provider or specific skills funding body (e.g.the BFI).

If you want to contact us about your marketing preferences please contact [data.protection@screenskills.com](mailto:data.protection@creativeskillset.org) or call on 02077139800

## Information that we may collect

When you visit the ScreenSkills website, we may collect and process the following information about you, which includes “personal data” as defined in the Act:

  * Information you provide to us – You may provide us with information by completing forms on or otherwise submitting information to the ScreenSkills website, or by corresponding with us via email, telephone, post or otherwise. This might include information you give us when you register to use the ScreenSkills website, create a account, create a swarm, post comments, apply for a training programme delivered by us or one of our partners, make purchases, “like” content, ask or answer questions, thank other users of the ScreenSkills website (Users) for advice, “follow” other Users, update your profile, apply for vacancies, search for courses, participate in discussions or other functions of the ScreenSkills website, report offensive content or another problem with the ScreenSkills website, or when you respond to specific questions from us. The information you give us may include your name, address, email address, photograph, portfolio, employment details, education details, skills, audience, industry sector(s) and other details about your professional life that you provide to us. Some or all of this information may be publicly visible on the ScreenSkills website and may be displayed in search engine results and in recommendations to other Users.
  * Information about you that we collect – Each time you access the ScreenSkills website we may collect the following technical information about the way in which you accessed the ScreenSkills website: the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; your login information; your browser type and version; your time zone setting; your browser plug-in types and versions; your operating system and platform, traffic data, location data, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouseovers); weblogs and other communications data.
  * Information about your use of the ScreenSkills website – Each time you access the ScreenSkills website we may collect the following technical information about your use of the ScreenSkills website: the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from the ScreenSkills website (including date and time); page response times; download errors; length of visits to certain pages; page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs); and methods used to browse away from the last page visited. We may also keep a record of any telephone number that you call us from.
  * Information we receive from other sources – If you give us permission, we may also retrieve information from your LinkedIn, Google, Facebook or Twitter accounts when you register on the ScreenSkills website. Some or all of this information may be publicly visible and may be displayed in search engine results.

  * Information provided to us when you communicate with us for any reason, whether via email, letter, through the ScreenSkills website or via our helpline.

Personal information collected by the ScreenSkills website is often limited to contact details and some basic information about your area of work and employment status, but may include other information necessary to provide a particular service you have requested.

Sensitive, including special category personal data may include data about your ethnic origin, nationality, gender, membership of a trade union or association, employment status, sexual orientation, caring responsibilities, number of children and, in some cases, your socio-economic background. If you are under 18 you will need to ensure your parent provides us with their consent for you to provide sensitive data about yourself.

If you are applying for a service for which government funding is available, you may need to answer certain additional questions such as your age and your current education and employment status, in order for us to evaluate whether you are eligible for that funding. By providing your information to the ScreenSkills website, you explicitly give your consent for us to process your personal and sensitive data. However, when we collect sensitive personal data through the ScreenSkills website, we will ask you to consent to our uses of the data, and you may choose not to give us this consent if you so desire. Wherever the provision of information is optional, this will be made clear.

We will treat any information we collect in accordance with this Policy.

## Cookie and user tracking

A “cookie” is a small text file deposited on your device’s hard drive when you access a website. Please read our Cookie Policy which sets out details of the cookies used on the ScreenSkills website.

## How we use the information about you that we collect

The information that we collect and store relating to you is primarily used to enable us to provide our services to you. In addition, we may use some or all of the information about you for the following purposes:

  * To provide you with information requested from us (such as event invitations, publications or e-newsletters) or information on other products or services (including general updates about the ScreenSkills website, our partner organisations or carefully selected third parties) which we feel may be of interest to you, where you have consented to receive such information.
  * To meet our contractual commitments to you.
  * To display your profile in our directories and elsewhere on the ScreenSkills website
  * To notify you about any changes to the ScreenSkills website, such as improvements or service/product changes, that may affect our service.
  * To deal with your comment or query, and to contact you for more information regarding a comment or query you have made.
  * To arrange and deliver services you have requested, whether online, one-to-one or via the telephone.
  * To administer our site and for internal operations including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, and surveys.
  * To generate anonymous statistics to help us improve the services we offer to you (these statistics will not include information that can identify you as an individual). Sometimes we may ask you whether we can keep personal sensitive data linked to an individual learning record. This can happen when we want to monitor the progress of individuals from different backgrounds through and beyond a training programme. It may also occur when we are required to share your data with a funding organisation (like the BFI) or a training provider partner. Giving personal sensitive information is always voluntary and we will explicitly ask your permission and/or your parent’s permission to share it, and any reported statistics based on it will still be anonymous.
  * To ensure that the Equal Opportunities Policy is effective, a monitoring of applications, approvals and placements is carried out. The collected sensitive information regarding your gender, age, ethnic group, sexual orientation, caring responsibilities and in some cases socio-economic background, and any disability you may have, is used solely for monitoring purposes and will be treated as confidential.
  * To pre-populate forms on the ScreenSkills website requesting information you have already provided, for your convenience and ease-of-use.
  * to assess your professional needs and attributes in order to match you with other Users, and to identify content, resources and vacancies appropriate for you and those other Users
  * to request resources appropriate for you from third parties (for example, LinkedIn)
  * depending on your settings and where you subscribe for updates, for the purpose of sending you those updates (see below for details on adjusting your privacy settings)
  * depending on your settings, to share your information with trusted third parties carefully selected by us so that they can send you updates (see below for details on adjusting your privacy settings)
  * to administer our site and for internal operations including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, and surveys
  * to link your LinkedIn, Google, Facebook or Twitter profiles to your ScreenSkills profile if you choose to do so (which may involve us sending your information to LinkedIn for that purpose).

Occasionally, we (or trusted third parties carefully selected by us) may wish to send you information about our (and/or their) products, services and activities.  Before you are sent any such information, we will ask whether you wish to receive such information.  If you confirm that you do wish to receive such information and/or your parent confirms to us that it is OK for you to receive such information, you are consenting to the use of your personal information (and, if applicable, the sharing of it with such trusted third parties) for that purpose. If you confirm that you do not wish to receive such information, we will not use your personal information, and we will not share it with such trusted third parties, for that purpose. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us by email at: [data.protection@screenskills.com](mailto:data.protection@screenskills.com).

## When information about you may be accessed by others

Occasionally, we (or trusted third parties carefully selected by us) may wish to send you information about our (and/or their) products, services and activities.  Before you are sent any such information, we will ask whether you wish to receive such information.  If you confirm that you do wish to receive such information and/or your parent confirms to us that it is OK for you to receive such information, you are consenting to the use of your personal information (and, if applicable, the sharing of it with such trusted third parties) for that purpose. If you confirm that you do not wish to receive such information, we will not use your personal information, and we will not share it with such trusted third parties, for that purpose. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us by email (see below for details of how to contact us).

## Where we store your personal information

All information you provide to us is stored, usually within the UK or other parts of the European Economic Area (EEA), on secure servers hosted by us or third parties providing hosting or other services for us.

We store application details including personal, sensitive data in electronic forms which are filed on our secure intranet. Hard copies of application forms are stored in lockable cabinets in a secure office environment.

Owing to matters such as financial or technical considerations the information you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA), which are not subject to the same data protection regulations as apply in the UK. We may do this as some corporate systems are hosted on servers outside of EEA e.g. USA, Switzerland etc.

We meet our obligations under GDPR by ensuring that the information has equivalent protection as if it were being held within the EEA. We do this by ensuring that there are appropriate safeguards in place with any third parties processing your data outside the EEA. This will usually be because the country either benefits from an adequacy determination for GDPR purposes and/or, where appropriate, we have entered into a Data Processing Agreement with the third party which contains model EU clauses or the third party works under EU-US Privacy Shield Framework.

## Information security

We take every reasonable precaution to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information and to ensure that it will be processed in accordance with this Policy. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of data sent to us electronically.  You acknowledge and accept that, despite our efforts to protect your personal information, there is a risk that others may try to intercept the personal information you provide to us. Transmission of your information is entirely at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password so that you can access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.

## Disclosing and sharing your information

We will not disclose your personal information to third parties, except where the data may be provided to a third party company, such as an email newsletter tools e.g. Mail Chimp or web agency, for the sole purpose of delivering a service on the ScreenSkills website’s behalf (provided you, or your parent if you are a child, have consented to this).

Your personal data - your name address, contact details etc. - will only be shared with partners or funders connected by contract with the training opportunity you have applied for. Where we need to share it with a specific organisation, e.g. the BFI, we will ask your (or, if you are a child, your parent’s) permission to do so.

Your sensitive personal data including special category sensitive data, concerning characteristics such as your gender, ethnicity, disability or sexual orientation is always asked for on a voluntary basis - you can choose not to say - and diversity statistics gathered through our monitoring systems are always reported anonymously.

We may disclose your personal information if we are required to do so under any legal obligation and may use external data for the purposes of fraud prevention and credit risk reduction, or where doing so would not infringe your rights, but is necessary and in the public interest.

Other than this, we will not share your information with other organisations without your consent.

## Course information and third party links

The ScreenSkills website has taken care to ensure that the information on the ScreenSkills website is correct. However, no warranty, express or implied, is given as to its accuracy and the ScreenSkills website does not accept any liability for error or omission. The ScreenSkills website is not responsible for how the information is used, how it is interpreted or what reliance is placed on it. We do not guarantee that the information on the ScreenSkills website is fit for any particular purpose. You should also be aware that the availability of courses of study is subject to conditions applied by individual institutions at their sole discretion.

You will find links to third party websites on the ScreenSkills website. These third party websites should have their own privacy policies which you should check before you submit any personal data to them. We are not responsible and do not accept any liability for the privacy practices or content of such websites. The ScreenSkills website does not endorse any of the products or services of third party organisations contained within its sites unless expressly stated.

ScreenSkills has taken care to ensure that the information on the website is correct. However, no warranty, express or implied, is given as to its accuracy and ScreenSkills does not accept any liability for error or omission. ScreenSkills is not responsible for how the information is used, how it is interpreted or what reliance is placed on it. We do not guarantee that the information on the website is fit for any particular purpose. You should also be aware that the availability of courses of study is subject to conditions applied by individual institutions at their sole discretion.

You will find links to third party websites on the Website. These third party websites should have their own privacy policies which you should check before you submit any personal data to them. We are not responsible and do not accept any liability for the privacy practices or content of such websites. ScreenSkills does not endorse any of the products or services of third party organisations contained within its sites unless expressly stated.

## Your rights

You have the right to request details of the personal details and or processing activities that we carry out with your personal information through making a Subject Access Request.  Such requests have to be made in writing. On or after 25 May 2018 no charge may be made under GDPR except in very limited circumstances, which will be explained to you if relevant. More details about how to make a request and the procedure can be found on our Data Subject Access Request page.

You have the following rights: (as introduced in the UK under the GDPR in May 2018):

  * the right to request rectification of information that is inaccurate or out of date
  * the right to erasure of your information (known as the 'right to be forgotten')
  * the right to restrict the way in which we are dealing with and using your information, and
  * the right to request that your information be provided to you in a format that is secure and suitable for re-use (known as the 'right to portability');
  * rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling including profiling for marketing purposes.

All of these rights are subject to certain safeguards and limits or exemptions, further details of which can be found in our Data Protection Policy.  To exercise any of these rights, you should contact Data Protection Officer(s) at [data.protection@screenskills.com](mailto:data.protection@creativeskillset.org)

If you are not happy with the way in which we have processed or dealt with your information, you can complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office.  Further details about how to complain can be found on our complaints page.

## Freedom of Information

The Freedom of Information Act 2000 (FOA) provides public access to information held by public authorities. It does this in two ways:

  * Public authorities are obliged to publish certain information about their activities; and
  * Members of the public are entitled to request information from public authorities.

The FOA covers any recorded information that is held by a public authority in England, Wales and Northern Ireland, and by UK-wide public authorities based in Scotland. Information held by Scottish public authorities is covered by Scotland's own Freedom of Information (Scotland) Act 2002.

The ScreenSkills website is not a public body, and therefore is not directly subject to the FOA. The list of public bodies covered by the FOA can be found [here](https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations). We will respond to requests for information from members of the public, where the provision of information in response to such an enquiry does not adversely affect the ScreenSkills website or its stakeholders. This is entirely at the discretion of the ScreenSkills website, and we are in no way compelled by the FOA to respond to such requests. All Freedom of Information requests should be sent to Data Protection Officer(s) at [data.protection@screenskills.com](mailto:data.protection@creativeskillset.org).

## How to contact us

If you have any questions on this Privacy Policy or our use of your personal information, you can email us at: [data.protection@screenskills.com](mailto:data.protection@creativeskillset.org).

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We keep this Privacy Policy under regular review and we may, from time to time, update or otherwise modify this Privacy Policy. We will notify you of any changes to this Privacy Policy by posting the modified Privacy Policy on the ScreenSkills website. If you then continue to use the ScreenSkills website, you will be confirming your consent to our use of your information as set out in the modified Privacy Policy. You are encouraged to check the terms of this Privacy Policy whenever you visit the ScreenSkills website.

This policy was last modified on 27/09/2018.
